{
    "id": "3298849477bc47b4a7fe9783494a69f8",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Sam ................................... his homework for two years.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous tense is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "was doing",
                "is doing",
                "has been doing"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a5fdda7f3ac343fda017915f5045ad20"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ................................ a strange experience yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to say when something happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "72310f89d61049e483bc2722da2f6ac9"
        },
        {
            "question": "He .................................... for Singapore last week.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to say when something happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "had left",
                "has left"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c0f625d441b54b668db29407390e29ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "See that you ................................... disturb the patients.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative structures.",
            "answers": [
                "do not",
                "did not",
                "is not"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "553150ecc4ef4d8282b7343ed2202465"
        },
        {
            "question": "You will win if you .................................. hard.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use the simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.structures.",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "worked",
                "have worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "98c92fa42ab14493a445196c683dba48"
        },
        {
            "question": "The post mortem report proved that the man ........................................ ten hours ago.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has been killed",
                "had been killed",
                "was killed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "613eff87d3cc46c1b26fe680e0dd79a8"
        },
        {
            "question": "The train .................................. by the time we reached the station.",
            "description": "We use the past perfect for the earlier of two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a97170cd405a44a2a4ee35c2fbd3aced"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every morning, I .................................. for 30 minutes.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habitual actions in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "meditated",
                "am meditating",
                "meditate"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0ca16490f4ab4175b6b96422ef53c174"
        },
        {
            "question": "He .................................... school at fifteen.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to talk about finished past events. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "545a0bc552974b40987e157ee1efbd46"
        },
        {
            "question": "You cannot meet him now. He ................................ home.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished events whose effect is still felt in the present.",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "has gone",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "62367704d77042eb927575f71d87b9c5"
        },
        {
            "question": "When we visited her she ................................. bed ridden for six months.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ee52089977e2499385a6171946fdff46"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………………… to me, you wouldn’t land in trouble.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "listen",
                "listened",
                "have listened"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6ded907bdd5245e28c17b6afc84437d1"
        }
    ]
}